Guide to the WDBS Collection, 1949 - 1983 UA.31.12.0005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
WDBS collection
1949-1983
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
WDBS (Radio station: Durham, N.C.)
UA.31.12.0005
8 Linear Feet
WDBS was Duke University's campus radio station from 1950-1983. It initially broadcast on AM by carrier current, a system in which radio signals were fed into the university's electrical system. In 1971, WDBS began broadcasting on FM 107.1 as a commercial, non-profit station. AM broadcasts ceased in the early 1970s. WDBS was sold in 1983 to repay debts the station owed Duke University. Collection includes annual reports, correspondence, proposals, newspaper clippings, advertising, program guides, record company photographs and press releases, and other materials related to the operation of WDBS. There are also reel-to-reel sound recordings of broadcasts from the 1960s and 1970s, including speeches by Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., Stokeley Carmichael, Douglas Knight, Samuel Dubois Cook, Charles Goodell, Robert Shelton, Spiro Agnew, Julian Bond, Birch Bayh, William Kunstler, Floyd McKissick, Richard Kleindienst, and Terry Sanford. News events and other subjects represented on tape include the 1968 Vigil, the 1969 takeover of the Allen Building by the Afro-American Society, racial unrest in Durham, anti-war activism, the 1971 USA Pan-Africa track meet, the 1972 Republican National Convention, the dedication of the William R. Perkins Library, and the Duke Symposium. Musical recordings include an organ recital, the Concert Band, and the Glee Club. English.
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Use of audiotapes from this collection requires the creation of reference copies. Reference copies for a few of the tapes have been made on audiocassettes, and if a reference copy exists, it is noted in this finding aid. To arrange for the creation of reference copies of other items, please contact University Archives staff. Although these recordings are now stored in a stable environment, their condition and playback quality is unknown.
Provenance
The WDBS Collection was received by the University Archives as transfers and gifts in 1969, 1972, 1974, 1979, 1981, 1996, accession numbers UA69-55, UA72-55, UA72-78, UA74-25, UA74-187, UA79-95, UA81-71, UA96-95.
Historical Note
WDBS was Duke University's campus radio station from 1950-1983. It initially broadcast on AM by carrier current, a system in which radio signals were fed into the university's electrical system. In 1971, WDBS began broadcasting on FM 107.1 as a commercial, non-profit station. AM broadcasts ceased in the early 1970s. WDBS was sold in 1983 to repay debts the station owed Duke University.
In 1947, three classmates from Rocky Mount, NC started a carrier current station called WCDC (for "We cover Duke campus".) They were persuaded to make their station an official university activity, and in 1950, WDBS began broadcasting from the basement of the Gray Building. In 1963, WDBS moved to the Bivins Building on East Campus.
In addition to music, the station presented campus news, national news, Duke athletics, and coverage of special events, including the 1968 Vigil after the death of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., the 1969 Allen Building takeover, and anti-Viet Nam War activities.
In 1971, WDBS purchased its FM license from Durham's WSRC. AM broadcasts continued for a time but ceased soon thereafter. Although owned by Duke, WDBS-FM operated independently as a commercial but non-profit entity. Initially run by students, by 1975 it was primarily staffed by professionals. The station was known for its extensive record collection, free form rock programming, and coverage of local events.
The purchase of the FM license, made possible by a long term loan from the university that was to be repaid from advertising revenue, put the station into debt from which it never recovered. Talk of selling the station's license, in order to pay back the debt to the university, began in the mid-to-late 70s.
In May 1978, WDBS agreed to sell its license to Village Broadcasting of Chapel Hill, pending approval from the Federal Communications Commission. Durham residents opposed to the sale petitioned the FCC to stop the license transfer. In October 1979, the Board of Directors of WDBS withdrew from the sale, citing the lack of approval from the FCC.
In 1980, the station moved from Bivins to Broad Street. In an attempt to increase listenership, WDBS changed its format from rock to classical during the day and jazz at night. In August 1982, WDBS agreed to sell to Classic Ventures, Ltd., pending approval by the FCC. The sale was approved in April 1983 and WDBS became an easy listening station. In 1984, it became WXFC.
There are some connections between WDBS and the later FM station, WXDU. In 1974, the unused AM carrier current system was revived as WDUR, playing Top-40, rock, and jazz. In 1977, WDUR became WDUK after a local commercial station petitioned the FCC for the call letters WDUR. In 1977, when the sale of WDBS was being considered, WDUK staffers proposed that students take over and operate WDBS. This proposal was eventually rejected. When WDBS moved off campus in 1980, WDUK moved into its former studios. In 1983, WDUK began broadcasting on FM as WXDU.
Collection Overview
Collection includes annual reports, correspondence, proposals, newspaper clippings, advertising, program guides, record company photographs and press releases, and other materials related to the operation of WDBS. There are also reel-to-reel sound recordings of broadcasts from the 1960s and 1970s, including speeches by Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., Stokeley Carmichael, Douglas Knight, Samuel Dubois Cook, Charles Goodell, Robert Shelton, Spiro Agnew, Julian Bond, Birch Bayh, William Kunstler, Floyd McKissick, Richard Kleindienst, and Terry Sanford. News events and other subjects represented on tape include the 1968 Vigil, the 1969 takeover of the Allen Building by the Afro-American Society, racial unrest in Durham, anti-war activism, the 1971 USA Pan-Africa track meet, the 1972 Republican National Convention, the dedication of the William R. Perkins Library, and the Duke Symposium. Musical recordings include an organ recital, the Concert Band, and the Glee Club.
Related Material
Joseph C. Wetherby Papers, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Vice President for Business and Finance Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Celester Wesson Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Bibliography
WDBS: Blue Devil Network, Duke University Alumni Register 36: Oct. 1950, pp. 239-241.
Jeff Miller, Remembering WDBS: The Campus Radio Station of Duke University (1950-1983), http://geocities.com/wdbs560/
Civil rights demonstrations -- North Carolina -- Durham; African American student movements; African Americans -- North Carolina -- Durham -- Political activity; Broadcasts; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975 -- Protest movements -- United States; Students -- Political activity; Sound recordings; Student movements -- United States; College radio stations; Cook, Samuel DuBois, 1927-; Duke University -- History -- 20th century; Duke University -- Students -- Political activity; Duke University. Afro-American Society; Bayh, Birch, 1928-; Bond, Julian, 1940-; Agnew, Spiro T., 1918-1996; Carmichael, Stokely; Sanford, Terry; WDBS (Radio station: Durham, N.C.); McKissick, Floyd B. (Floyd Bixler), 1922-; Kunstler, William Moses, 1919-; Shelton, Robert M.; King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1929-1968; Goodell, Charles E. (Charles Ellsworth), 1926-1987; Knight, Douglas M., 1921-2005; Kleindienst, Richard G., 1923-
- Annual Reports, 1951-1970
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes annual reports from the station manager, engineering manager, public relations manager, business manager, production manager, news editor, and other staff members. Also included are profit and loss statements, correspondence regarding equipment, equipment diagrams, program schedules, and other materials related to the operation of WDBS.
  - Annual reports, 1951-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1-15)
- Correspondence, Clippings, Histories, etc., [1949]-1983, undated
  - A Student Radio Station to Cover Duke Campus: Proposal, [1949] (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Charter, Bylaws, Operational Code, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Clippings, 1970-1983, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Most of the clippings concern events surrounding the proposed sale of the station in the 70s, a proposal by WDUK to assume the operations of WDBS and give control of the station back to students, community opposition to the sale, and the final sale of the station in 1983.
  - Correspondence, 1950-1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Memos and correspondence, including a 1950 plan for installing a campus radio station and a 1966 report on the feasibility of a campus FM station.
  - Financial: Budgets, Advertising Brochures, etc., 1960-1968, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - History of Radio Station WDBS, Part I, 1947-1957. J. Robert Brubaker, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - History of Radio Station WDBS, Part II, 1958-1968. J. William Veatch, III, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - News Wire Reports, circa 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Printed teletype reports from United Press International (UPI). Most of the news stories pertain to 1968 presidential primaries.
  - Miscellany, 1954-[1978], undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Bumper stickers, promotional items, and other materials.
  - WDBS-FM: Loan Request Proposal with Exhibits and Related Data, copy 1, 1970 July 11 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - WDBS-FM: Loan Request Proposal with Exhibits and Related Data, copy 2, 1970 July 11 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Radio Council, 1965-1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Radio Council Petitions for Positions, circa 1962-1970 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Wiring Diagrams, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - WDBS 107.1 FM Stereo, circa 1974, UA96-95, poster (Oversize-folder MC20)
  - Your Radio Station, 1971, UA81-71, 12 inch phonograph record, one-sided (Audio-disc D1)
- Program Guides, 1973-1980
  The WDBS Program Guide began as a weekly pamphlet that listed the week's programming. By 1974, it published monthly, accepted advertising, and featured articles, fiction, poetry, photography, and a calendar of local cultural events.
  - Program guides, 1973-1980 (Box 3, Folder 30-35)
- Record Company Promotional Materials, circa 1970-1980
  Photographs, posters, press releases, and other materials supplied to WDBS by record companies.
  - Promotional materials (Box 4)
- Audiotapes, 1956-1973, undated; 5
  - Interviews, addresses, and other news coverage, 1960-1973, undated; 1
    - Post-Christian Man Symposium Reel 1: Herberg, 1960 November 15-1960 November 17 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0001)
    - Post-Christian Man Symposium Reel 2: "Nature of the Predicament", 1960 November 15-1960 November 17 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0002)
    - Post-Christian Man Symposium Reel 3: "Reactions of Man and Society to the Predicament" #2, 1960 November 15-1960 November 17 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0003)
    - Post-Christian Man Symposium Reel 4: Hopper, 1960 November 15-1960 November 17 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0004)
    - Post-Christian Man Symposium Reel 5: "Alternatives in Dealing with the Predicament" #2, 1960 November 15-1960 November 17 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0005)
    - Post-Christian Man Symposium Reel 6, 1960 November 15-1960 November 17 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0006)
    - Post-Christian Man Symposium Reel 7: Driver, 1960 November 15-1960 November 17 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0007)
    - Post-Christian Man Symposium Reel 8, 1960 November 15-1960 November 17 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0008)
    - Glenn Negley: Last Lecture, 1961 March 9 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0009)
    - Martin Luther King, Jr.: Page Auditorium, 1964 November 13 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0010)
      Scope and Contents
      UA79-95-20
    - Symposium on the South in Continuity and Change: Allan Sindler, 1965 February 22 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0011)
    - Symposium on the South in Continuity and Change: Joseph J. Spengler, 1965 February 22 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0012)
    - Rosa Weinstein Lectures: Dr. Martin Fox, 1966 February 16-1966 February 17 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0013)
    - Symposium: Newcomen Society, 1966 April 14; 10 inch reel (Box 9, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0014)
    - Stokely Carmichael: Interview, 1967 March (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0015)
      UA79-95-21
    - Stokeley Carmichael: Page Auditorium, 1967 March (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0016)
      UA79-95-22/23
    - Middle East Crisis, 1968 March 8-1968 March 9; 10 inch reel (Box 9, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0017)
    - Dr. Knight's Address: Page Auditorium, part 1, 1969 May 12 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0052)
    - Dr. Knight's Address: Page Auditorium, part 2, 1969 May 12 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0053)
    - University Convocation, 1969 September 25 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0057)
      ASDU President Robert C. Fedlman; Provost Marcus Hobbs; Chancellor Barnes Woodhall
    - Senator Charles Goodell: Baldwin Auditorium, 1969 November 12 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0058)
    - WDBS feed from Washington, part 1, 1969 November 14 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0059)
    - WDBS feed from Washington, part 2, 1969 November 14 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0060)
    - WDBS feed from Washington, part 3, 1969 November 14 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0061)
    - WDBS feed from Washington, 1969 November 15 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0062)
    - Robert Shelton, 1969 November 28 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0063)
      Address by Robert Shelton, Imperial Wizard of the KKK (United Klans of America). Provided by C. P. Ellis, President Durham Unit #9 United Klans of America, Inc. A note from C. P. Ellis included with the tape is in Box 6, Folder 36.
    - Terry Sanford: Press Conference, 1969 December 14; 3 inch reel (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0064)
    - Activism Potpourri, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0065)
      1. Quad forum report by Ken Ross, 1968-1969; 2. Actuality from President Knight's home during the Allen Building crisis, February 1969; 3. Dubs from quad rally; 4. Howard Fuller in Page Auditorium, February 15, 1969; 5. Tom Fine in Washington, November 15, 1969 march; 6. Tom Fine in Washington, November 15, 1969 march; 7. John Deal, October, 1969, Divinity School on Moratorium; 8. Quad rally; 9. Don Baumgartner, November 15, 1969 moratorium
    - Dedication of Chapel Organ, 1969 April; 10 inch reel (Box 9, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0051)
    - Esso Educational Seminar, 1969 June 24-1969 June 25; 10 inch reel (Box 8, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0054)
    - Esso Educational Seminar, 1969 June 25-1969 June 26; 10 inch reel (Box 8, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0055)
    - Esso Educational Seminar, 1969 June 27; 10 inch reel (Box 8, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0056)
    - Perkins Library Dedication: Terry Sanford, 1970 April 15 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0066)
    - Dedication of W. R. Perkins Library: Page Auditorium, 1970 April 15 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0067)
    - Perkins Library Dedication, 1970 April 16 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0068)
    - Cambodia: Duke Protest Rallies, 1970 May (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0069)
    - Cambodia, 1970 May (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0070)
    - Cambodia, 1970 May (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0071)
    - Cambodia and Kent State Demonstrations, 1970 May 5-1970 May 7 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0072)
    - Terry Sanford Inauguration, part 1, 1970 October 18 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0073)
    - Terry Sanford Inauguration, part 2, 1970 October 18 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0074)
    - Terry Sanford Inauguration, part 3, 1970 October 18 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0075)
    - Spiro Agnew at Reynolds Coliseum, 1970 October 27 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0076)
    - Spiro Agnew at Reynolds Coliseum, 1970 October 27 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0077)
    - Terry Sanford, Baldwin Auditorium, part 1, 1970 November 7 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0078)
    - Terry Sanford, Baldwin Auditorium, part 2, 1970 November 7 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0079)
    - Mayday Coverage, Washington, DC, Tape #1, 1971 May 1-1971 May 2 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0080)
    - Mayday Coverage, Washington, DC, Tape #2, 1971 May 3 (Box 6, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0081)
    - Mayday Coverage, Washington, DC, Tape #3, 1971 May 4 (Box 7, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0082)
    - City Council Reports, 1971 June 21 (Box 7, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0083)
    - Pan-Africa USA Track, 1971 July 17 (Box 7, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0085)
    - City Council Reports; Pan-African Track Meet, 1971 July 18 (Box 7, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0084)
    - Julian Bond in Baldwin Auditorium, 1971 September 12 (Box 7, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0086)
    - Julian Bond in Baldwin Auditorium, 1971 September 12 (Box 7, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0087)
    - Senator Birch Bayh: Page Auditorium, 1971 September 22 (Box 7, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0088)
    - Terry Sanford: Southern Regional Growth Board Keynote Address, 1971 October 3 (Box 7, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0089)
    - Senator Fred Harris: Page Auditorium, 1971 October 18 (Box 7, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0090)
    - William Kunstler: Page Auditorium, part 1, 1972 January 20 (Box 7, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0091)
    - William Kunstler: Page Auditorium, part 2, 1972 January 20 (Box 7, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0092)
    - Floyd McKissick: Gross Chemistry Building, 1972 February 16 (Box 7, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0093)
      Speaker during "Black Week" with Greg Kern & Anthony Steward.
    - Richard Kleindienst: Gross Chemistry Building, 1972 April 11 (Box 7, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0094)
    - North Carolina Primary Election, 1972 May 6 (Box 7, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0095)
    - Presidential Candidate Terry Sanford, Primary Night Statement, 1972 May 6 (Box 7, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0096)
    - Republican National Convention, 1972 August 19-1972 August 21 (Box 7, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0097)
    - Republican National Convention, 1972 August 22 (Box 7, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0098)
    - Louis Redden, 1972 August 23 (Box 7, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0099)
    - Louis Redden, 1972 August 23 (Box 7, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0100)
    - Nixon: Vietnam Peace, 1973 January 23 (Box 7, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0101)
    - Folk Festival, undated; 10 inch reel (Box 8, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0102)
    - Folk Festival: 2nd Nite, undated; 10 inch reel (Box 8, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0103)
    - Folk Festival: Workshop, undated; 10 inch reel (Box 8, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0104)
    - Friends of Library, undated; 10 inch reel (Box 8, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0105)
  - WDBS Tapes of the Duke Vigil, 1968 April 5-1968 April 10; 2
    - Vigil #1, 1968 April 5 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0018)
      1 sound tape reel (1200 ft.): 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. UA68-347-1; Pete Seeger Spots by Paul Robert Conroy; In the Beginning: Friday night, April 5, 1968, Speech in the Alumni Lounge by Dr. John Strange to the group just before marching to Dr. Knight's home.
    - Vigil #2, 1968 April 5 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0019)
      1 sound tape reel (1200 ft.): 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. UA68-347-2; Dr. Knight at home-talks with Jack Boger and Jon Kinney, commentary by Ken Ross, Dave Birkhead, Paul Robert Conroy. Ken Ross with 20 minute actuality on Dr. Knight talking to the vigil at his home, questioned by Jack Boger, et al.
    - Vigil #4, 1968 April (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0020)
      John Strange (Alumni Lounge) as on tape no. 1; Statements by: Dean William Griffith; Dr. James Graham; Tupp Blackwell for the S.S.O.C.; Mr. Ted Minah; University spokesman (Bindewald); Dave Birkhead; Chris Jossi; The original tape no. 4 from the WDBS collection described above does not correspond to any of the dubbed tapes in the Duke Vigil collection. Tape no. 4 in the Duke Vigil collection is labeled: WDBS Tapes of the Duke Vigil, no. 4, April 8, 1968-April 10, 1968 Press conference, continued: John Strange, Bunny Small, John Kinney. Dr. Martin Luther King's "I have a dream" speech played several times to the assembled vigil on the quad. Wednesday, April 10, 1968, main quad: John Strange and Wright Tisdale addresses, singing of "We shall overcome." This tape from the Duke Vigil Collection does not seem to directly correspond to any of the tapes in the WDBS Collection.
    - Vigil #5, 1968 April 6 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0021)
      1 sound tape reel (1200 ft.): 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. UA68-347-5; At Dr. Knight's House, April 6, Sat. p.m.; a. Huck Gutman-on Local 77 Strike; b. Questions on the 4 demands; c. WDBS Actualities (most same as #4); Mr. Ted Minah-statement on strike; Mr. Bindewald-same; Mr. Ted Minah-appeal for student workers; d. Jack Boger-on what to do now; e. Dr. John Strange-same; f. Law student, Dave Hunt
    - Vigil #7, 1968 April 7 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0022)
      1 sound tape reel (1200 ft.): 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. UA68-347-7; Sunday, April 7, 1968, on the main quad: Dr. John Strange, reading from Dr. King; Bunny Small recaps the past 43 hours; Jon Kinney; general announcements; comments on the Black students; Huck Gutman, reading Thoreau; Algerian grad student
    - Vigil #8, 1968 April 7 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0023)
      1 sound tape reel (1200 ft.): 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. UA68-347-8; Sunday, April 7, 1968, cont. rally on the main quad: Singing led by Nick Atkins, organizer for Local 77, et al.; Announcements by Lucy Brady, Food Committee; Chairman Tape of Dr. Martin Luther King's "I have a dream" speech, Washington, 1963
    - Vigil #10, 1968 April 8 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0024)
      1 sound tape reel (1200 ft.): 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. UA68-347-11; Rally on the Main Quad, cont.; Questions and answers from the assembled Duke Vigil to and from: Mr. Ira Sanford, Miss Joan Baez, Mr. David Harris
    - Vigil #11, 1968 April 10 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0025)
      1 sound tape reel (1200 ft.): 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. UA68-347-9; a. Address by Dr. Samuel Dubois Cook to the assembled Vigil, Wednesday. April 10, 1968, time, ten minutes. b. Statement to the students of Duke University, read to the assembled Duke Vigil, by Wright Tisdale, Chairman of the Board of Trustees, Wednesday, April 10, 1968, Time: five minutes.
    - Vigil #12, 1968 April 10 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0026)
      Speeches on the Main Quad 1. Dr. John Strange; 2. Mr. Wright Tisdale, Chairman, Duke University Board of Trustees (same as 11); 3. Dr. John Strange (remarks on #2); 4. Replay of speech by Dr. Samuel D. Cook to the assembled Vigil by WDBS (same as 11)
    - Vigil: Baez, 1968 April (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0027)
      1. Ira Santel? [Sanford]; 2. Joan Baez; 3. David Harris; at the Duke Vigil on the Main Quad
  - Allen Building Takeover, 1969 February 10-1969 March 12; 3
    - Allen Building Crisis: Tape #1, 1969 February 13 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0028)
    - Allen Building Crisis: Tape #2, 1969 February 13 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0029)
    - Allen Building Crisis: Tape #3, 1969 February (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0030)
    - Page Meeting, part 1: Tape #4, 1969 February 13 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0031)
    - Page Meeting, part 2: Tape #5, 1969 February 13 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0032)
    - Dick Gregory Visit, Allen Building Takeover: Tape #6, 1969 February 10, 1969 February 17 (Box 5, Audio-reel UA31120005-RR-0033)